We'll start by looking at this data set.
سنبدأ بإلقاء نظرة على مجموعة البيانات هذه.
It's a list of leads for Posh and Posy,
إنها قائمة من عمليات البيع المحتملة في Posh وPosy،
prospective customers whose business that they might try to win.
وهما عبارة عن عملاء متوقعين لهم أعمالهم الخاصة وقد يحاولون تحقيق أرباح.
Please keep in mind that this isn't anybody's real personal information.
يُرجى أن تضعوا في الاعتبار أن هذه ليست معلومات شخصية حقيقية لأي شخص.
This was randomly generated for the sake of this lesson.
تم إعداد هذا الأمر عشوائيًّا من أجل هذا الدرس.
Our goal here is to clean up this data set,
يتمثّل هدفنا هنا في تنظيف مجموعة البيانات هذه
to make it more useful for analysis.
لجعلها مفيدة أكثر لإجراء التحليل.
For text fields, that means making clean groups that will be useful to aggregate across.
في حقول النص، يعني هذا إنشاء مجموعات نظيفة ستكون مفيدة عند التجميع.
Let's start by pulling the area code out of the phone number.
لنبدأ بسحب رمز المنطقة من رقم الهاتف.
Since the structure of a phone number in this data set is always the same,
نظرًا لأن بنية رقم الهاتف في مجموعة البيانات هذه هي نفسه دومًا،
we can use that to our advantage.
يمكننا استخدام هذا لصالحنا.
The area code is always the first three characters of a phone number.
دائمًا ما يكون رمز المنطقة هو الأحرف الثلاثة الأولى من رقم الهاتف.
We can get this using a left function.
يمكننا الحصول على هذا باستخدام دالة اليسار.
You can use left to pull certain number of characters from the left side of the string,
يمكنكم استخدام اليسار لسحب عدد معيّن من الأحرف من الجانب الأيسر في السلسلة،
and present them as a separate string.
وعرض هذه الأحرف كسلسلة منفصلة.
If we just want the phone number,
إذا كنا نريد رقم الهاتف فقط،
we can use right, which does the same thing but from the right side.
يمكننا استخدام دالة اليمين، التي تؤدي الوظيفة نفسها لكن من الجانب الأيمن.
Right works well in this case,
تكون دالة اليمين مناسبة في هذه الحالة،
because we know that the number of characters will be
لأننا نعرف أن عدد الأحرف سيكون
consistent across the entire phone number field.
متسقًا عبر حقل رقم الهاتف بالكامل.
If it wasn't consistent,
إذا لم يكن متسقًا،
it's still possible to pull a string from the right side,
فسيظل بالإمكان سحب سلسلة من الجانب الأيمن،
in a way that makes sense.
بطريقة تبدو مفهومة.
The length function returns the length of the string.
تقوم دالة الطول بإرجاع طول السلسلة.
So, the length of the phone number will always return 12 in this dataset.
إذًا، سيقوم طول رقم الهاتف دومًا بإرجاع العدد 12 في مجموعة البيانات هذه.
Since we know that the first three characters will be the area code,
نظرًا لأننا على علم بأن الأحرف الثلاثة الأولى ستُمثّل رمز المنطقة،
and they'll be followed by a dash.
فستتبعها شرطة.
So, total of four characters.
حسنًا، إجمالي أربعة أحرف.
We could represent the right function as a function of the length.
يمكننا تمثيل دالة اليمين كدالة الطول.
As you can see, the results in the phone number alt field are the
مثلما ترون، تكون النتائج الموجودة في حقل رقم الهاتف alt
same as the result in the phone number only field.
هي نفس النتائج الموجودة في حقل رقم الهاتف فقط.
This is because, length of the phone number minus four
يرجع هذا إلى أن طول رقم الهاتف ناقص أربعة أحرف
is going to resolve as twelve minus four or eight.
سيُحل على أنه اثنا عشر ناقص أربعة أو ثمانية.
Which is the same as the phone number only call.
وهو نفسه عند الاتصال برقم الهاتف فقط.
When using functions within other functions,
عند استخدام الدوال داخل دوال أخرى،
it's important to remember that the innermost functions will be evaluated first,
من المهم تذكّر أن الدوال الأعمق سيتم تقييمها أولًا،
followed by the functions that encapsulate
تليها الدوال المضمنة